SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Summary

Highly energetic and meticulous IT professional with 2+ years' experience in developing Java J2EE applications. Expert in software life cycle, including programming, maintaining, troubleshooting and updating of java applications. Profound ability to work with very little supervision accompanied with great analytical thinking and trouble shooting ability. 2+ years of Professional Java/J2EE Software Development experience of Core Java and Web based applications with expertise in reviewing client requirement; prioritize requirements, creating project proposal (scope, estimation) and baseline project plan. Participated in entire Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) including Requirement Analysis, Design, Development, Testing, Implementation, Documentation and Support of software applications. Application development using Core Java, Servlets, JSP, Spring, JDBC, Hibernate, JPA and MVC architecture. Experience in using MVC (Model View Controller) architecture for developing applications using JSP and Servlets. Experience in front-end application using HTML, CSS, spring and JSP. Extensive experience with design and development of J2EE based applications involving technologies such as Java Server Pages (JSP), Java Data Base Connectivity (JDBC), Java Naming and Directory Interface (JNDI). Experience using Hibernate for mapping Java classes with database and using Hibernate query language (HQL). Experience in designing Use Cases, Class diagrams, Sequence and Collaboration diagrams for multi-tiered object-oriented system architectures. Experience in various methodologies like Waterfall and Agile. Experience in Database Design, Creation and Management of Schemas, Stored Procedures, Functions, SQL queries. Excellent team player with equally good leadership skills. Highlights

- J2EE Technology
- Servlets, JSP, Tag Libraries, JDBC, JPA.
- Programming Language
- Java, J2EE, Python
- Architecture & framework
- MVC, Spring 3.8, Hibernate 3.5.
- Database
- SQL server 2005/08, DB2, PostgresSQL, MySQL
- IDF
- Eclipse, My Eclipse, NetBeans, PyPE.
- Operating Systems
- Windows 9x/NT/XP/2003/7/8/10, Linux, Unix, Macintosh.
- Data Structure Formats
- XML,JSON,GSON
- Technologies
- Artificial Intelligence, Search Engine Information Retrieval
- Version Control Systems
- GitHub, Subversion(SVN)

Accomplishments

- Search Engine A fully functional search engine.
- Using different tactics such as PageRanking, Tfldf, ranking, crawling, content analysis and detection, and query models.
- Used technologies such as Jsoup, Jackson, Gson & Tika for information retrieval.
- All the retrieved data from a web link or a file can be stored in database or Json file for further data requirements to implement ranking and display search result based on that ranking algorithm.
- Github Link https://github.com/harry162/CS-454.SEO Contested-Massive Multiplayer Online Role Playing Game Worked as team leader and contribute in implementation of server program.
- Implemented heartbeat for update all online player's moves with other players and environment which was most challenging for us.
- Github Link https://github.com/harry162/Contested_MMORPG Tic Tac Toe Created an Online multiplayer game using Java's spring framework and JSPs.
- Graphically strong game which was uploaded on server and can be played by two players from different computers.
- Github Link https://github.com/harry162/Tic-Tac-Toe Course Planner Created a course planner with the use of JAVA and JSPs.
- Students can schedule their courses and its plans via this.
- Github Link https://github.com/harry162/Course_Planner.

Experience

Software Engineer 04/2015 to 10/2015 San Francisco, CA

- consultant to handle billing and processing refunds in ServiceLink portal.
- Processed billing through XML transfer using web services with the use of batch process.
- Handled XML billing code development and XML parsing and XML insertion.
- Involved in enhancement of RefundRequests project to handle customer's refund request through the use of client's inbound request file everyday through batch process.
- Developed an application to generate a report excel file of previous month's business for Kaiser Permanente.
- Used SVN version controller to maintain the code version.
- Environments: Java 1.6, JDBC, XML, Oracle 11g, DB2, Maven 3.0.5, Spring 3.8, TotrtoiseSVN, RESTful Web Services.

Web Design Intern 10/2014 to 01/2015 Doubledutch New York, NY

- Worked as an intern to develop website based on JAVA platform.
- Done a client-side programming focusing on the designing and layout of the website.
- This includes SQL scripting for the Database and use of CSS for Graphics.
- Developed web Components using JSP, Servlet under J2EE Environment.
- Implemented MVC architecture using Servlets, JSP.
- Created MVC architecture built on struts framework.
- Developed the DAO layer for the application using Spring Hibernate Template support.
- Used SVN version controller to maintain the code versions.
- Used Maven build tool to build the application.
- Environment: Java 1.6, JSP, Servlets, CSS 2.0, Oracle 10g, Eclipse 3.1, Maven, Spring 3.8, Hibernate 3.5, Web Sphere Server, SVN.

Java Developer 08/2011 to 07/2013 Cvs Health Mount Prospect

- Development, enhancement and testing of the Web Methods flow services and Java services.
- Used web services for interaction between various components.
- Created a Front-end application using JSPs and Spring MVC for registering a new patient and configured it to connect to database using Hibernate
- Used Spring Security for Authorization of users and implemented Spring Web-Services.
- Developed and configured Microsoft SQL Server 2008 tables including Sequences, Functions, Procedures and Table constraints.
- Created standalone Java programs to read data from several JSON files and insert data into the Database as needed by the Testing team.
- Developed and provided support to many components of this application from end-to-end, i.e.
- Front-end (View) to Web Methods and Database.
- Provided solutions for bug fixes in this application.
- Environment: Java 1.5, Spring 2.5, Spring Web Services, Spring Security, Hibernate 3.0, cxf, Microsoft SQL Server 2008, Eclipse.

Education

Master of Science: Computer Science March 2015 California State University City Computer Science Bachelor of Engineering: Computer Engineering June 2013 Gujarat Technological University Computer Engineering Skills

Artificial Intelligence, billing, consultant, controller, CSS, CSS 2.0, client, Version Control, DAO, Database, designing, Eclipse 3.1, XML, Graphics, DB2, Web Sphere, IDE, J2EE, Java, Java 1.5, Java 1.6, JSP, JDBC, JSON, layout, Linux, Macintosh, excel, Windows 9, NT, MVC, MySQL, Operating Systems, Oracle, Programming, Python, read, Servlet, Servlets, scripting, Microsoft SQL Server, SQL, SQL server, struts, tables, Unix, View, website